Myron Buchstane Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Myron Buchstane Papers.
1942 - 1945
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Buchstane, Myron
0.8 linear feet (1 box)
Collection consists of letters written by Myron Buchstane, a World War II Air Force officer stationed in the Pacific's Mariana Islands, to his parents and siblings.
Biographical Sketch
Myron E. Buchstane was a member of the 314th Bomb Wing, 572nd Materiel Squadron, Army Air Force. While stationed on the Mariana Islands in the Pacific, he served as assistant trial judge advocate on the court martial board.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of letters written by Myron Buchstane, a World War II Air Force officer stationed in the Pacific's Mariana Islands, to his parents and siblings.
Materials are organized into two series based on arrangement by the donor.
Series I: Correspondence contains letters mentioning American prisoners of war who were on the Bataan Death March, soldiers wounded at Iwo Jimo, Radio Tokyo propaganda and rationing on the home front.
Series II: Air Force Base Newsletters comprises the publication "This Is It!", distributed at the air force base in the Mariana Islands where Myron Buchstane was stationed. Includes photoprint illustrating how clothes are washed in a Korean village.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is open; additional material is not expected.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Buchstane, Myron
Corporate Names
United States. Army Air Force. 314th Bomb Wing. 572nd Materiel Squadron.
Subjects
World War, 1939-1945 --Prisoners and prisons.; World War, 1939-1945 --Propaganda.; Iwo Jima, Battle of, 1945.; Rationing, Consumer.
Contents:
- I. Correspondence
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1944 Jan.-Jul. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1944 Aug.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1945 Jan.-Mar. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1945 Apr.-May (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1945 Jun.-Aug. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1945 Sep.-1946 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Myron to his family. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Myron to his family., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Myron to his mother., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from Myron to his mother., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Myron to his mother., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters from Myron to his sister Grace, 1945 and undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters from Myron to his sister Sarah, 1945 and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters from Myron to his brother Joseph, 1945 and undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- II. Air Force Base Newsletters
  - Amateur Journal "This Is It!", 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)